（殴る音）
（カイト）うっ。　教えろ！　フリーセル！
Tell me, Freecell!
本当に…　俺のせいで…
お前の母親は…。
Was it really my fault that your mother...
（フリーセル）ふん。
マジ　分かんねえ…。
I don't get it!
俺が　何をやって…
何が　どうなったのか…。
What did I do? What happened?
俺は　真実を知りてえんだ！
残酷だね…　カイトは。
I want to know the truth!
You're so cruel, Kaito.
Even though you try, you can't remember.
君は　思い出そうとして
思い出せないけれど→
僕は忘れたくても　忘れられない。
But even if I want to, I can't forget.
それを　僕に言えって言うの？
あっ！
Do you want me to say such a painful thing aloud?
君には　自ら
真実を思い出す義務がある。
You must remember the truth by your own will.
そうだろ？　カイト…。
Isn't that right, Kaito?
ゲーム　楽しみだね。
Let's enjoy the game.
くそっ！
God dammit!
lost te saguri de sagashiteta
Lost, trying to find it blindly with my hands.
tozasareta mirai no kotae nante doko ni mo nai
But the key to the locked future is nowhere to be found.
hashiru shoudou ima kaidoku funou
Undecipherable urges surging.
found kudaketa hazu no unmei wo
I found the fate I believed broken.
mijukuna yume no naka de kikoetekitan da
I heard it in my immature dream.
saigo made I'll be there for you
I'll be there for you till the very end.
tachitomaranai kono hari dake wa
I can't stop. I hear nothing else.
boku no asu wo kizamu oto tsukisasu
How this needle carves my future.
shinjitsu kara nigetara ima
I'm running away from the truth now.
genjitsu ni mo maketara ima
I'm losing to reality now.
nani ga nokoru no (nokoru no)
What will be left?
kazoekirenai kono kizu dake ga
The countless scars on my body
boku no kinou wo zanzou toshite kataru
are the only thing telling the story of my past.
unmei ga hodokete mo ima
Even if fate falls apart now,
sonzai wo kowashite mo ima
even if existence shatters now,
boku no michi wo yuku yo
I'm walking down my own path.
It's now or never.
This is what they say: "Live your life today."
There will always be, there will always be a way.
The Truth of Smiles
（キュービック）今のカイトに
パズルなんて　とても無理だ。
Kaito can't solve puzzles right now.
確かに　アナのおかげで
どん底からは　脱した。
Sure, thanks to Ana, he's not at rock bottom anymore.
でも　根本解決には遠い。
But the solution is still so far away.
（アナ）アナが思うに　闇の中の本当が
見えないから　カイトは動けない。
I think... he can't act because he can't see the truth in the darkness.
だね…。
あぁ…。
Yeah...
（ノノハ）私　何のために
ついてきたんだろう…。
Why did I even bother coming here?
何もしてあげられない。
I can't do anything for him.
まだかな…
軸川先輩からの連絡…。
Jikugawa still hasn't responded.
僕の推論が証明されれば
カイトを救えるかもしれないのに…。
If my theory is correct, we may be able to save Kaito.
（ソウジ）
ＰＯＧの全システムを使っても→
Even using the POG's computing power, it still takes this long to analyze the data...
これほど　データ解析に
時間がかかるとは…。
（バロン）私の出る幕はありませんね。
ん？！
I have no role in this game, do I?
学園長！　いつから？
Principal! How long have...
（バロン）自ら考え　現状で
最善の行動をとる。
You think, analyze the situation, and act as you deem suitable.
成長したものです。
You've grown.
ギャモン君や　キュービック君もですよ。
Gammon and Cubic have too.
つまり　それほどまでに状況は…
深刻です。
The situation is very grave.
（ダウト）
ゲームの形式を変更するだと？！
You're changing the rules of the game?
（ホイスト）はい。　残り２つの対戦
すなわち　ダウト様　対　ギャモン様→
Yes.
The remaining two games of Sir Doubt vs Sir Gammon and Sir Freecell vs Sir Kaito
フリーセル様　対　カイト様のゲームを１つにし
２対２のタッグバトルといたします。
will be held as a 2v2 tag team battle.
（ミゼルカ）タッグバトル？
（メランコリィ）どういうことなの？　ホイ。
A tag team battle?
What's the meaning of this, Whi?
My name is Whist,
ホイストでございます　メラ様。
Lady Mela.
メ・ラ・ン・コ・リィ！　ふん！
Me-lan-cho-ly! Hmph!
（ウェイター）お待たせいたしました。
うわ～！　ステキ！
Your order, ma'am.
So cute!
（ダウト）納得できんな。
I can't accept this.
You're changing the sacred rules of the game when it's just about to begin.
神聖なる決闘の形式を
寸前に変えるなど。　理由は何だ？
What's your reason?
（フリーセル）いいんじゃない？
別に　どうでも。
Oh, come on. It's not like it matters.
カイトと遊べる。
それに変わりはないんだから。
I can still play with Kaito. That's all that matters.
フリーセル！
恐れ入ります。
Freecell!
Pardon my interruption, but...
クロンダイク様も　今回の変更には
いたく　お喜びのご様子。
it appears that Lord Klondike is overjoyed by this change as well.
ぬあっ。　クロンダイク様が…？
Lord Klondike is?
ならば　やむをえまい…　いや…→
Then I've got no choice.
クロンダイク様のご意思とあらば
謹んで…。
Or rather, if it's what he wishes, I shall endure.
Eh?!
ええっ？！
ギャモンが？！
You did it?
そうだ。　俺が要求した。
Yeah, I requested that they make the last game a tag team battle.
ラストゲームをタッグバトルにしろってな。
どうして　そんなことを？
Why would you do that?
俺とカイトで　一気に
勝ち星を２個　もぎ取る。
Kaito and I will take two victories at once.
そうすりゃ　３勝２敗で
俺たちの勝利だ。
Then we win three games to two.
文句ねえな？　カイト。
That's fine with you, isn't it, Kaito?
カイト　どこ行くの？
Where are you going, Kaito?
顔　洗ってくる。
やるからには…　ぜってえ　勝つ！
To wash my face.
Now that we're doing this...
we gotta win.
カイト。
きついね。　あの状態じゃ…。
Kaito...
It'll be tough in his state.
（ギャモン）だから　タッグバトルにした。
（ノノハ・キュービック）ん？！
That's why I want a tag team battle.
できるかぎり　フォローはする。
それでも　つぶれるなら…→
I'll cooperate as much as possible.
But if we start losing,
俺は　カイトを見限る！
あっ。
I'm giving up on him.
ギャモン君…。
勘違いすんな。　俺のためだ。
Gammon...
Don't get me wrong. It's for my sake.
あのバカが　元気でいてこそ→
Only when he's at full power can my genius truly shine.
ギャモン様の天才っぷりが
引き立つってもんだからな。
うん！
僕も　やる。　カイトのために！
I'll do what I can for him as well!
アナは応援する！
私も。
I'll cheer for him!
Me too!
アナ。　一緒に応援しよう。
いいとも！
Ana, let's cheer for him together!
Okie!
（ギャモン）おい！　俺も応援しろ。
努力する。
Hey, cheer for me too!
I'll try.
ふん。　今　てめえにやれることを
精いっぱい　やろうぜ。
Do what you can with all your might!
死ぬ気でな！
As if your life was on the line!
それでは　ただいまより
「リンク・スライダー」のラストゲームを行います。
The Rink Slider's last game shall now begin.
カイト様　フリーセル様　ギャモン様　ダウト様の
順番で　一手ずつ　スライダーを選び→
The order of moves is Sir Kaito, Sir Freecell, Sir Gammon, and finally, Sir Doubt.
You are to use the sliders to move horizontally and vertically.
前後左右　任意の方向へ滑走。
障害物に当たったところで
停止します。
Sliders stop if there is anything in the way.
移動できない場合は
パスを認めます。
If you cannot move, passing is acceptable.
チームのうち　１人が　中央のゴールに
到達すれば　勝利。
If one person from either team reaches the center,
勝ち点２を獲得し　同時に
総合勝利も手にします。
that team is awarded two victories, and therefore, wins the whole battle as well.
However, I have established special rules for this game.
（ホイスト）なお　今回は
特殊ルールを設けました。
リンクの４か所のパネルに停止すると
スライダーが　そこから動いたとき→
If a player stops at one of the four special squares,
a dust hole will appear as soon as the slider moves from that spot.
ダストホールが出現。
そのプレーヤーが　次に移動するまで
消えません。
It will not disappear until that player moves again.
In this game, teamwork is key.
この形式では　チームプレーが鍵。
敵だけじゃなく　パートナーの動きも
先読みしないと…。
They must predict their enemies' and their ally's moves.
（キュービック）できるのか？
今のカイトに…。
Can Kaito do that now?
それでは　ラストゲーム　プレー。
And now, last game: play.
Kaito, you can do it!
カイト　頑張って！
カイト～！
Kaito!
Let's go!
いくぜ！
いくよ　カイト。　レッツ　プレーアップ。
It's time, Kaito. Let's play up!
うっと。
ふん。
うっ。
うぁ。
バカ野郎！　気を抜くな！
Pay attention, you 'tard!
あぁ…。
次に　あのスライダーを動かすと→
The next time that slider moves, a hole will open which limits the moves they can make.
穴が現れて　移動の選択肢を
狭める。
難しいよ　このパズル。
This puzzle is difficult!
あっ？！
うれしいよ　カイト。
I'm so happy I can play with you like this, Kaito.
こうやって　君と遊べるなんて。
うっ…。
ずっと待ってたんだ…
君のこと…。
I've been waiting a long time for this.
ずっと…。
A long time...
きっと喜んでる…
天国のママもね。
I'm sure even Mommy is happy in heaven.
な　なんだ？！　今の感じ…。
What is this feeling?
（ギャモン）カイト！
あっ。
Kaito! Pay attention to the fucking puzzle!
パズルに集中しろ！
余計なこと　考えんじゃねえ！
Don't let your mind wander!
ふん　くだらん！
Pathetic.
長期戦になるとは思っていたけど。
（ピノクル）悪くないバトルだね。
I expected it to take a while.
This battle isn't half bad.
１人を除けば…　ですわ。
Except for a certain someone.
カイト…。
いつものキレがない。
Kaito...
He's not as sharp as usual.
チームプレーでも　相手に押されてる。→
Even now, he's just being pushed around.
なんとか　ギャモンがフォローしてるけど
それも　いずれ追いつかなくなる。
Gammon is covering for him, but this won't work forever.
その時が　敗北の時…。
At that point, we'll lose.
うっ…　連絡さえ　来れば…。
If only he would respond...
まだですか？　軸川先輩…。
How much longer, Jikugawa?
はぁ　はぁ　はぁ　はぁ。　こっちだ！
This way!
俺は…　本当に俺は…
あいつの母親を…。
I really... His mother really...
Because of me...
そうだよ。
あっ？！　くっ。
That's right.
君が死なせた…。
You killed her.
傷つき　悲しみながら
死んでいった…。
You made her die hurt and sad.
Because you broke your promise to me.
君が…　僕との約束を
破ったから…。
わ　分かんねえ…。
I-I don't get it...
俺が　約束を破って…
どうして　お前の母親が…。
What does my promise have to do with your mother?
My kind and beautiful Mommy...
優しくて　きれいなママ…
僕の宝物…。
My treasure...
そのママを　君は僕から奪った。
You took Mommy away from me!
それが　真実のすべてさ！
That's the only truth that matters!
はぁ。　ルーク。
（雷鳴）
Rook...
心の声
なぜ　なぜだ？　どうして
フリーセルが…　ルークと同じ目を…。
Why? Why?!
Why does Freecell have the same eyes as Rook?
いや～。　き　嫌い…　ぞっとするの。
あの…　笑顔…。
No... I hate that smile...
It makes me tremble...
笑ってる…。
どうして？
He's laughing...
But why? He blames Kaito for his mother.
カイトは　お母さんの敵なんでしょ。
なのに　どうして笑えるの？
So how can he laugh?
あはっ！
（ダウト）心弱き大門カイト。
Daimon Kaito, you are weak-hearted.
我ら
オルペウス・オーダーの敵ではないわ。
You are not an enemy of the Orpheus Order.
惑わされるな！　カイト！
うわっ。
Don't let them fool you, Kaito!
カイト　君の番だよ。
Kaito, it's your turn...
うふっ…　でも動けないか…。
But you can't move.
じゃあ　パスだね。　うふふふふっ。
So pass.
ダメだ。　カイトは　もう
パズルに集中できない。
カイト。
Oh, no! Kaito can't concentrate on the puzzle anymore!
Kaito...
そうさ…　君が約束を破ったから…
ママは死んだ。
That's right...
Mommy died because you broke your promise.
約束は守ってもらうよ。
And now you're going to keep that promise.
分からねえ。
心の声
約束…　約束って…。
I don't get it...
Promise? What promise?
Keep fighting me with puzzles until your life burns out!
僕と　パズルで戦い続けろ！
命　尽きるまで。
君は　それを拒めない！
You can't refuse!
何だよ…　それ…
何で…　俺が　お前と…。
What? Why do I have to...
君が　約束を破り
ママを殺したからさ。
Becuase you broke your promise and killed Mommy!
カイト。
Kaito...
約束　約束って　一体　何なのよ？！
"Promise! Promise!" What the hell is he talking about?
That guy's nuts.
あいつ…　何なんだ…
一体　何がしてんだ？　カイトに。
What does he want from Kaito?
早く…　解析は　まだなのか…。
Come on... Hurry up with the analysis!
来た！
It's done!
これは…。
No way!
No, Kaito! Don't do-
違う　カイト！　それじゃ…。
助言は　ルール違反だ！
Assisting him is against the rules.
はぁ…　俺は…　俺は負けねえ！
I... I won't lose!
来た！　軸川先輩からだ。
Finally! It's from Jikugawa!
あっ？！　キューちゃん。
Cubie!
やっぱり　僕の推論どおりだ。
I knew it! My theory was correct!
チャンスだ！　次に　カイトが
心の声
動けば　ゴールまで　あと３手。
This is our chance!
If Kaito moves correctly, we can win in three moves!
だが　今のカイトに
心の声
その手が読めるのか…。
But will he be able to predict that?
ふっはっ。　そうは　させん。
You won't have it your way.
まずい！　ここで　カイトが
心の声
フリーセルの進路をふさがなけりゃ→
Dammit, if Kaito doesn't stop Freecell right now, they're gonna win!
心の声
フリーセルの勝利が確定する！
Kaito! Hey, Freakaito!
カイト！　おい！　バカイト！
しっかりしろ！　カイト！
Get your shit straight, Kaito!
（フリーセル）どうしたの？　カイト！
あっ。
What's wrong, Kaito?
つまらないよ。
もっと　もっと遊ぼうよ　僕と！
You're boring.
Play with me more! More!
ははははっ　はははっ　ふふふっ
はははっ　あはははっ　わははっ！
何なの？　彼。
≫あはははっ！　わはははっ！
What's wrong with him?
あの子…　ママが好き。
えっ？！
He loved his Mommy.
でも　きっと
カイトのことも　大好き…。
But I think he loves Kaito too.
そんな…　じゃあ　何で笑えるの？！
But... then how can he laugh?
カイトを苦しめて
どうして笑えるの？！
How can he laugh while making Kaito suffer?
（アナ）
あの笑顔は…　本物じゃない…。
His smile is fake...
That's right!
（キュービック）そのとおりだよ。
あっ。
キューちゃん。
あいつの心は　壊れてる。
Cubie?
His heart is broken!
えっ？！　壊れてる。
Broken?
カイト！　解析結果が出た！→
Kaito, I got the analysis results!
彼らは　オルペウス・リングに
飲まれてるんだ！
Their hearts have been taken over by the Orpheus rings!
キュービック君は　ゲームの間　ひそかに
オルペウス・オーダーの脳波や→
Cubic secretly recorded the brain functions of the Orpheus Order members during their games.
精神活動のデータを
採取していました。
それを　ＰＯＧのコンピューターで
解析した結果…。
The POG analyzed that with their supercomputers...
オルペウス・リングが　常時発動し→
Their Orpheus rings are constantly active.
彼らは　その強大な力に
飲み込まれている。
As a result, they have been overwhelmed by that humongous power.
はい。
Exactly.
They can't maintain their sanity like that!
（キュービック）そんな状態で
理性が保てるわけがない！
思考も感情も　極度に
ゆがめられてるはずだよ。→
Their logic and emotions are all extremely warped!
フリーセルの言う真実に
確証なんかない！
Nothing supports the "truth" Freecell is talking about!
Don't believe him, Kaito!
信じちゃダメだ！　カイト！
ふん！　くだらん世まい言を。
我らは　ファイ・ブレインの子供。
Pathetic nonsense!
We are the children of the Phi Brain.
We merged with the Orpheus rings and have taken control of them!
オルペウス・リングと一体化し　我らが
リングを支配しているのだ。
かつてのルークも　そう信じて
疑わなかった。
Rook didn't doubt anything because he believed that as well!
でも…。
あっ！
But...
（キュービック）ゆがんだ友情と
野望を携え　カイトに牙をむいた。
His warped hopes and friendship made him attack Kaito!
あれは　オルペウス・リングに
飲み込まれた目…。
Those are the eyes of someone overwhelmed by the Orpheus rings!
カイト！　思い出して！　約束！
Kaito! Remember your promise!
「すべてのパズルは　俺が解く！」って
言ったでしょう！
"I'll solve every puzzle!" That's what you said!
私たちとの約束！
That's your promise!
守れ～！
Keep it!
勝負は…　これからだ。　フリーセル。
The battle starts now, Freecell.
カイト！
Kaito!
カイト…。
…ったく　手間かけさせやがって。
Kaito...
Damn, you sure know how to cause trouble.
いくぜ　ギャモン！
Let's do this, Gammon!
It's your turn.
さあ　お前の番だぜ。
くっ…　パスだよ…　カイト。
I pass, Kaito.
へっ　それでいい！
Perfect.
今こそ　誠の決闘を！
The time for the true battle has come.
すごいよ！　カイト…　ギャモン…。
２人の息が　ぴったり合ってる。
Amazing!
Kaito and Gammon...
They're in perfect sync!
けっ　追いつかん！
ダウトが　バトルから　はじき出された！
I can't catch up!
They shut Doubt out of the fight!
It's over!
これで終わりだ～～！
They did it! We win!
やった！　ゴール確定だ！
ウィナー　カイト様　ギャモン様。
通算成績３勝２敗。
The winners are Sir Kaito and Sir Gammon.
With a total score of three wins and two losses,
決闘を制したのは
√学園の皆様です。
the Root Academy team wins the battle.
（手をたたく音）
（ノノハ・アナ）やった～！
Hurray!
勝った…　カイトが　勝った…。
We win... Kaito won...
助かったぜ　みんなのおかげで。
You guys saved my ass.
へっ　じゃあ　メシおごれや。
メガ盛りでな！
Then you're buyin' our next meal! Super sized!
You're eating every bite!
残すなよ。
ああ　ノノハ…　約束　守ったぜ。
Nonoha, I kept my promise.
Yeah.
（ダウト）バカな…　この俺が…
負けただと？！
Impossible... How could I lose?
うそ…　うそですわ…。
あれが…　大門カイト　真の力…。
No... No way!
That's... Daimon Kaito's true power.
フ　フリーセル…。
F-Freecell!
（フリーセル）
美しい…。　なんて美しいプレー…。
Beautiful...
Beautiful play...
すごいよ　カイト。
うあっ？！
You're amazing, Kaito!
カイト…　僕と…　僕と
パズルタイムを始めよう…。→
Kaito, let's have puzzle time together...
早く…　僕と。　さあ…　早く…。
Now... with me...
Now!
（ピノクル）大門カイト　フリーセルの心を
壊したのは　お前だ。
Daimon Kaito, you broke Freecell's heart!
Kaito, let's play more puzzles!
さあ　カイト　もっとパズルをやろう…。
ふふふっ　はははっ。
√学園の皆様　お引き取りを。
I must request that the Root Academy team leave.
たとえ　オルペウス・リングに
飲み込まれていても…→
Even if he's overwhelmed by the Orpheus Ring,
フリーセルの中では真実なんだ。
inside Freecell's head, that's the truth.
俺が　やつの母親を
死なせたってことは…。
I killed his mother.
アナが思うに　もし
それが本当なら→
I think... if that's true, then you're a bad person.
カイトは悪い人…
償わなきゃいけない…。
And you should repent for that.
アナ。
闘って　光を当てるの。
Ana?
Fight and give them light...
闇の中の本当に。　その光で
あの子を温めてあげて　カイト。
And then warm his heart with that light, Kaito.
まっ　このまま　おとなしく
引き下がるような→
Well, I can't really imagine them just giving up quietly after this.
お歴々でもないだろうしね。
ぱしっとな！
They won't have it easy as long as I'm alive!
いつでも返り討ちにしてやんぜ！
なっ！　カイト。
Right, Kaito?
ああ…　やるぜ！　俺は。
Yeah, I'm with you.
本当に悪いのは　誰なんだろう？
I wonder who's really in the wrong here...
フリーセル　あいつとは　ガチで
パズルをやる。
I'll give it my all when I'm solving Freecell's puzzles.
必ず　その時が来る！
I know that time will come.
（ホイスト）このたびは　興味深いデータを
数多く採取できました。
We have gathered a significant amount of fascinating data.
とりわけ　ラストゲームのタッグバトルでは…。
Especially in that last tag team battle.
敗北を喫しましたフリーセルたちの
処分は　いかように？
How should I deal with Freecell's team?
（クロンダイク）必要ない…。
That is unnecessary.
まだ　使い道はある。
We can still use them.
eiyuu kidori itsu datte shinjita muteki no kankaku
I think I'm a hero and believe that I'm invincible.
tatakatte iru no wa chikyuu no tame nanka janai
I'm not fighting for the world.
motto mai peesu de
It's for a more personal,
sou motto shoujikina negai no tame
a more honest wish.
nando to naku kizutsuite mo
No matter how many times I'm hurt